A Guide to the Governor John Page Executive Papers, 1802-1805
Library of Virginia
Additional significant correspondence includes the following: William Dabney, Board of Inspectors of the Penitentiary, re. vacancies from the resignations of George Hay & Major Scott (1803 Jan. 13); John Page to Lt. Governor John Guerrant re. his absence (1803 Jan. 31, 1805 Aug. 19, & 1805 Oct. 16); John Tyler resigning as judge of the Court of Chancery in Williamsburg (1803 May 25); William Nelson., Jr., resigning as judge of the Court of Chancery in Williamsburg (1803 May 25 & June 1); Francis & Alexander Tubeuf re. payment to the colony of their deceased father Francis Peter de Tubeuf (1803 May 31); Mann Page re. his commission as chancellor for the Williamsburg District (1803 June 14); J. A. Chevallie, Agent for the representatives of the late Caron de Beaumarchais, re. the decree from the Court of Appeals against the State of Virginia (1803 Oct. 8); James Lownes, Micajah Davis, Thomas Ladd, & Thomas Elliott resigning as Inspectors of the Penitentiary (1803 Oct. 12); Anderson Barret re. an estimate of a house to keep the cannon (1803 Oct. 14); James Monroe, Minister to England, re. land disputes in Virginia with British subjects (1803 Nov. 29); Robert Mitchell resigning as Inspector of the Penitentiary (1804 Feb. 24); John Dixon soliciting appointment as Public Printer in the room of Meriwether Jones (1804 March 29); Samuel Pleasants, Jr., re. his appointment as Public Printer (1804 April 4); James Greenhow re. quarters for the Public Guard (1804 April 14); Edmund Randolph re. a case under his care (1804 May 12); Harry Toulmin, Secretary of State for Kentucky, re. counterfeiters (1804 May 14); Edmund Randolph re. the trial of Thomas Logwood in the U. S. Circuit Court (1804 May 24); Governor Page to the Council re. the case of Thomas Logwood (1804 May 28); John Marshall re. his opinion to guard Logwood who was convicted of a felony (1804 May 31); Edmund Randolph re. Thomas Logwood's case (1804 June 7); William Prentis, Mayor of Petersburg, re. the discovery of forged bank notes (1804 June 8); John Beckley, Clerk of the U. S. House of Representatives, transmitting copies of the journal (1804 June 11 & 1805 May 17); John Robinson re. the closing of the doors of the Capitol after hours (1804 Aug. 11); James Greenhow re. an infirmary for the Public Guard (1804 Aug. 25); John P. Shields enclosing a presentment of the Richmond District Grand Jury against Alexander Quarrier for erecting a necessary on Capitol Square near the spring leading to his house (1804 Sept. 25); Jacob Wagner, Chief Clerk of the Dept. of State, forwarding copies of the laws of the U. S., 2nd Session, 7th Congress (1804 Oct. 5); Governor Page to the President re. the Sierra Leone Company and permission to use their lands as an asylum or to use land in Louisiana for the removal of some 19,000 free negroes & mulattoes (1804 Oct. 29); Governor Page to the Governor of Kentucky re. the affidavit of David Greenlaw charging Joseph Morel & George Foley with the murder of Lewis L'Orient (1804 Nov. 5); Benjamin Woods, Deputy Attorney for the North Carolina District, re. David Greenlaw's affidavit (1804 Nov. 23); Benjamin Day, Mayor of Fredericksburg, re. suppressing the practice of gaming (1804 Dec. 13); Monsieur Oster enclosing the recognition of James Madison by President Jefferson of his official character as Sub Commissary of Commercial Relations for the Port of Norfolk (1804 Dec. 18); Robert Mitchell, Mayor of Richmond, re. unlawful gaming within the city & a fine for firing "Christmas guns" (1804 Dec. 25); J. Saunders, Capt. U. S. Artillery enclosing a return of ordnance & military stores at Fort Nelson & Norfolk and a monthly return of his company of artillerists (1805 June 30); William McKim re. an estimate for building the steeple at the Manufactory of Arms (1805 Aug. 22); George Goosley re. the sale of convicted slaves confined in the Penitentiary (1805 Aug. 23 & 24); P. D. Robert enclosing an extract of the memorials to the commissioners appointed for examining claims to lands in the Indiana Territory District of Kaskaskias (1805 Sept. 8); and Creed Taylor accepting his appointment as judge of the General Court to replace Joseph Jones (1805 Nov. 6).
Other noteworthy items include: a proclamation by Governor Page for the capture of George Case (1803 Jan. 7); bonds of William Moseley as Treasurer (1803 Jan. 13, 1804 Jan. 25, & 1805 Jan. 15); a memorandum of clothing to be furnished to the Public Guard by Thomas Underwood (1803 Jan. 13); a receipt from John Miles of 100 stand of arms delivered to John Shee in Philadelphia (1803 Jan. 28); a report of the committee appointed in relation to the President's message regarding the militia (1803 Feb. 7); a report of the commissioners for laying Richmond into wards (1803 Feb. 23); a bill of lading for arms shipped from Philadelphia by John Shee (1803 March 11 & 21); proceedings of the Board of Inspectors of the Penitentiary regarding the conduct of Martin Mims as Keeper (1803 March 3); proceedings of the Board of Inspectors regarding the Keeper's accounts (1803 March 25); a petition of the convicts in the Penitentiary asking for an allowance of chewing tobacco (1803 April 30); a proclamation by Lt. Governor John Guerrant regarding the capture of three escaped convicts (1803 April 30); advice of the Inspectors of the Penitentiary regarding Rule #15 and their temporary orders (1803 June 11); the commission of Mann Page as judge of the High Court of Chancery at Williamsburg (1803 June 11); a proclamation by Governor Page for a reward for the capture of Lewis McWane & John Boyd who escaped from the District Jail of Charlottesville (1803 Aug. 6); a report of vessels subject to quarantine by J. K. Read, Port Physician at Norfolk (1803 Sept. 23); a list of persons permitted by the Richmond District Court to qualify as citizens (1803 Oct. 1); a report by the commissioners on the status of the Treasury (1803 Oct. 3); a commission of Thomas Underwood as Superintendent of Public Tobacco Warehouse in Richmond (1803 Oct. 15); a proclamation by Governor Page revoking his previous proclamation to perform quarantine on vessels from New York & the West Indies (1803 Oct. 29); a bond of William Price as Superintendent of Public Tobacco Warehouse in Richmond (1803 Dec. 26); an oath of John Heath as Privy Councilor (1803 Dec. 30); a bond of Thomas Underwood as Superintendent of Public Tobacco Warehouse in Richmond (1804 Jan. 2); a proclamation by Governor Page for the apprehension of William Christe charged with murder (1804 Jan. 13); minutes of the committee appointed to examine into the cause of the escape of the prisoners from the Penitentiary (1804 March 31); a proclamation by Governor Page for the apprehension of Israel Wilkinson who escaped from the District Jail at Staunton (1804 March 31); a proclamation by Governor Page for the apprehension of Joseph Caldwell, Robert Peirson, & Cullen Demmory who escaped from the Penitentiary (1804 March 31); a proclamation by Governor Page for the capture of David Bowman who escaped from the sheriff of Hardy County (1804 May 30); a bond of Samuel Pointer for furnishing rations to the Public Guard (1805 March 26); a proclamation of Governor Page for a reward for the capture George Dilliard (1805 June 5); a return of the Richmond Republic Blues by Capt. George William Smith (1805 June 8); a proclamation for a reward for the capture of Joseph & John Thruston (1805 June 19); a proclamation of Lt. Governor John Guerrant regarding the quarantine of vessels from New York, Philadelphia, & the West Indies (1805 Sept. 21); a contract of William McKim for erecting the steeple of the Manufactory of Arms (1805 Nov. 2); a proclamation by Governor Page for a reward for the capture of David Phenix (1805 Nov. 2); and the bond of Samuel Pleasants, Jr., as Public Printer (1805 Dec. 6).
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by date of document with undated items arranged to the rear.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Flournoy, H. W., CALENDAR OF VIRGINIA STATE PAPERS, January 1, 1799-Dec. 31, 1807, VOL. IX, Richmond: J.H. O'Bannon, Superintendent of Public Printing, 1890.
Separated Material
Oversized materials have been separated into Oversized (Clamshell Box) and Oversized (Newspaper Box).
Contents List
- John Page Executive Papers
- 1802
  - December
- 1803
  - January
    - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 18-31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - February (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - March
    - 2-21 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 22-29 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - April
    - 3-15 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 16-30 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - May (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - June
    - 1-14 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 16-30 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - July
    - 1-14 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 17-30 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - August (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - September (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - October (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - November (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - December (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pardons
    - A-I (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - J-T (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 1804
  - January
    - 2-13 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - February (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - March
    - 1-23 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - April
    - 2-15 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 16-28 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - May
    - 2-10 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 11-19 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 21-31 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - June
    - 1-10 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 11-25 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 21-31 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - July
    - 2-14 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 20-31 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - August
    - 3-15 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 16-24 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 25-31 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - September
    - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 16-30 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - October
    - 1-13 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 19-30 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - November
    - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 16-29 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - December
    - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 17-29 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 1805
  - January
    - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 16-26 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - February
    - 4-15 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 16-26 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - March
    - 4-14 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 16-28 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - April
    - 3-15 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - 16-30 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - May
    - 1-20 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - 21-31 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - June
    - 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 11-20 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 21-30 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - July
    - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 16-30 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - August
    - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 17-31 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - September
    - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 16-28 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - October
    - 1-14 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 16-30 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - November
    - 2-15 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 16-30 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - December (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Oversized (Clamshell Box)
  - 1803
    - Jan. 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Jan. 6 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Jan. 26 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Feb. 19 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - April 27 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - April 29 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - May 4 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - May 13 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Aug. 20 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Oct. 8 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Oct. 15 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Oct. 15 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Nov. 4 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Dec. 1 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Dec. 13 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Pardons - Bill (Slave) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1804
    - Jan. 2 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Jan. 24 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Feb. 18 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Feb. 23 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - March 5 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - March 30 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - April 4 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - April 14 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - May 22 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - June 10 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - June 30 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - July 27 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Sept. 7 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Sept. 7 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Sept. 11 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Sept. 22 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Sept. 23 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Dec. 1 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Dec. 17 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - 1805
    - Jan. 26 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - March 14 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - April 5 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - May 18 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - May 18 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Nov. 28 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Nov. 29 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Nov. 30 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Nov. [N.D.] (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Oversized (Newspaper Box)
  - 1803
    - Jan. 4 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - April 30 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Nov. 10 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Pardons - Bob (Slave) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Pardons - Lewis (Slave) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Pardons - Holloway, Anderson (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1804
    - June 22 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1805
    - March 26 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - May 5 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - June 30 (Box 8, Folder 10)